Guide to Reginald Marsh: Thirty Etchings and Engravings 1930–1943 (1969) PR 341
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Reginald Marsh: Thirty Etchings and Engravings
1930–1943 (1969)
PR 341
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
1.5 Linear feet (1 box of 30 prints in a portfolio)
Thirty proof prints of etchings and engravings by Reginald Marsh, made from the artist’s original copper plates for distribution by the Whitney Museum of American Art, 1969.
Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from the Art Dealers Association of America, 2008.
Arrangement
The thirty prints are filed in numerical order. Numbers were penciled by the archivist in the lower right corner of the verso of each print.
Scope and Contents
This set of thirty proof etchings and engravings by Reginald Marsh (1898–1954) are part of an edition of 114 portfolios produced from the artist’s original copper plates for distribution by the Whitney Museum of American Art in 1969. The first hundred sets of prints were numbered 1/100 to 100/100. The remaining fourteen sets—of which this is one—were marked “proof,” unnumbered, and not meant for sale.
Information on Reginald Marsh’s printmaking, etching, and copper engravings, may be had from the introductory material housed with the collection. It includes a list of print titles in the portfolio, thumbnail images, dates, dimensions, and “S.” numbers, indicating their placement in Norman Sasowsky’s catalog Reginald Marsh: Etchings, Engravings, Lithographs (Praeger, 1956).
Engravings; Etchings
- Loco—Going through Jersey City, 1930 (Item 1)
  Scope and Contents
  "loco" = locomotive
- 2nd Ave. El, 1930 (Item 2)
- Merry-Go-Round, 1930 (Item 3)
- Irving Place Burlesk [sic], 1930 (Item 4)
- Gaiety Burlesk [sic], 1930 (Item 5)
- The Barker, 1931 (Item 6)
- Wall Street, 1931 (Item 7)
- Tenth Ave. at 27th Street, 1931 (Item 8)
- Steeplechase, 1932 (Item 9)
- Bread Line—No One Has Starved, 1932 (Item 10)
- Tattoo-Shave-Haircut, 1932 (Item 11)
- Star Burlesk [sic], 1933 (Item 12)
- Box at the Metropolitan, 1934 (Item 13)
- Erie R.R. Locos Watering, 1934 (Item 14)
  "locos" = locomotives
- Steeplechase Swings, 1935 (Item 15)
- Flying Concellos, 1936 (Item 16)
- Morning in May, 1936 (Item 17)
- Minsky’s New Gotham Chorus, 1936 (Item 18)
- Wooden Horses, 1936 (Item 19)
- Battery (Belles), 1938 (Item 20)
- Merry-Go-Round, 1938 (Item 21)
- Pickaback, 1938–9 (Item 22)
- Modern 1939 Venus (Item 23)
- Grand Tier at the Met, 1939 (Item 24)
- Coney Island Beach No. 1, 1939 (Item 25)
- Girl in Fur Jacket Reading Tabloid, 1940 (Item 26)
- Merry-Go-Round, 1940 (Item 27)
- Eltinge Follies, 1940 (Item 28)
- Bathers-in-the-Hudson, 1941 (Item 29)
- Two Girls Walking to Right, 1943 (Item 30)